<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HUGO on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HUGO on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 10:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions copy one git repository to another git repository</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub provies &amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; which are automatic actions that are ran on gitHub for you. This can be used to compile your code, compile your docker image, or do any arbitrary set of commands. This typically is done in software development to automatically push software between development and test. This is typically done to insure all the necessary code, configurations, etc necessary are checked into the source repository. Additionally this insures all the neccessary steps are done uniformly no matter which developer checks in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo install on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction HUGO is a static website rendering engine. Essentially you write a collection of Mark Down to files with headers, and HUGO can very rapidily theme an entire website. This website for instance is on the HUGO platform. Other very large sites like most likely the Kubernetes Documentation is also on HUGO. You end up with a &amp;ldquo;wordpress&amp;rdquo; like feel for the end user, however its actually static HTML that can be served up on git pages or any http server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 05:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Adam Pritchard&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet that is useful when writing markup to make sure the syntax is correct. Markdown is a syntax used to format text. It essentially is a short form version of Hypertext Mark Up Language (HTML). You can achieve similar formatting with far less effort and by writing in Markdown instead of HTML. There is a Live Demo of Markdown available. This is especially useful if you would like to see what the rendered interactively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
