<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UBUNTU on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UBUNTU on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.04 with CRI-Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.04 with Docker and CRI-Docker. We are using an r5.2xlarge on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Ubuntu 22.04. You can get by with a much smaller instance depending on what you plan to run.
Installation Update Ubuntu Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
## Update Ubunutu sudo bash sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y sudo apt autoremove -y # if you see kenerl updates you should reboot # init 6 Hostname Your hostname should be in /etc/hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workspace with Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Amazon Workspace is a hosted Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI). Amazon hosts your workstations in the cloud. Users can connect to their provisioned workstations through a client software provided by Amazon for many different platforms, including mobile. The key difference comparing this to EC2 instances, is the client software. With EC2 typically you use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) or Secure Shell (SSH). With Amazon Workspace utilize PCoIP or WSP. Both protocals work far superior for end user experience for responsivness, espically on lower speed networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y # Kernel Updates wanted a reboot sudo init 6 Install ubuntu-desktop (Gnome, Xwindows, etc) sudo apt-get install ubuntu-desktop -y Install XRDP sudo apt install xrdp net-tools -y # insure xrpd on on ipv4 sudo sed -i &amp;#39;s/^port=3389/port=tcp:\/\/:3389/g&amp;#39; /etc/xrdp/xrdp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
