<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KUBERNETES on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KUBERNETES on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 20:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HELM Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-helm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction &amp;ldquo;Helm is the best way to find, share, and use software built for Kubernetes.&amp;rdquo; Kubernetes is a great container orchistration tool, however managing all the yaml files associated with it become a huge undertaking. Helm is a tool that allows you to create templates for Kubernetes yaml files. Then you only have to manage a set a value pairs that are passed to your templates. This allows you to easily share packages of templates, and other people can easily bring your containers online only having to modify the values to match their needs to customize or configure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancher Desktop for Kubernetes and Docker on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rancher Desktop is a Kubernetes and Docker platform that is a replacement for Docker Desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ll be installing and configuring it using the installation guide provided in Rancher&amp;rsquo;s Documentation Rancher is a replacement for Docker Desktop. Rancher provies you helm, kubernetes, docker, the CRI runtimes of dockerd or containerd kubernetes. It integrates in nicely with WSL if you wish to use Linux instead of Windows. Additionally it lets you choose which version of Kubernetes you want to run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Kubernetes Website&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet.
This page contains a list of commonly used kubectl commands and flags.
Kubectl autocomplete BASH source &amp;lt;(kubectl completion bash) # set up autocomplete in bash into the current shell, bash-completion package should be installed first. echo &amp;#34;source &amp;lt;(kubectl completion bash)&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc # add autocomplete permanently to your bash shell. You can also use a shorthand alias for kubectl that also works with completion:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on RHEL 9 with CRI-O, and Podman. We are using an r5.large on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Setup DNS or atleast Hostname entries in your /etc/hosts file
echo `/sbin/ifconfig eth0 | grep &amp;#39;inet &amp;#39; | awk {&amp;#39;print $2&amp;#39;}` ${HOSTNAME} | sudo tee -a /etc/hosts Set selinux to permissive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>