<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 05:03:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Web Services (AWS) Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I will be installing and doing basic configuration of Amazon Web Services (AWS)&amp;lsquo;s Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11. AWS CLI is a shell based means to work with AWS. The CLI provides the ability to list out resources at Amazon like which EC2 instances are running, poke around S3 buckets, inspect pretty much anything at Amazon. It also provides advanced features like copying information to and from S3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancher Desktop for Kubernetes and Docker on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rancher Desktop is a Kubernetes and Docker platform that is a replacement for Docker Desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ll be installing and configuring it using the installation guide provided in Rancher&amp;rsquo;s Documentation Rancher is a replacement for Docker Desktop. Rancher provies you helm, kubernetes, docker, the CRI runtimes of dockerd or containerd kubernetes. It integrates in nicely with WSL if you wish to use Linux instead of Windows. Additionally it lets you choose which version of Kubernetes you want to run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Install &amp;ldquo;Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux&amp;rdquo; (EPEL).
sudo dnf install -y https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-9.noarch.rpm sudo dnf repolist sudo dnf makecache Install &amp;ldquo;Workstation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Server with GUI&amp;rdquo; (not both)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python HTTP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</guid>
      <description>python http server If you need a quick and easy webserver to copy files between servers, or from your server to your workstation all you need is Python, which is part of YUM and is on almost every redhat based linux server. Simple goto the directory you want to share, and a single command in the shell will start up a webserver that you can use to get your files copied over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on RHEL 9 with CRI-O, and Podman. We are using an r5.large on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Setup DNS or atleast Hostname entries in your /etc/hosts file
echo `/sbin/ifconfig eth0 | grep &amp;#39;inet &amp;#39; | awk {&amp;#39;print $2&amp;#39;}` ${HOSTNAME} | sudo tee -a /etc/hosts Set selinux to permissive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>