<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:20:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changing the colors in Terminal ZSH on Mac OS</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/mac-cli-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/mac-cli-colors/</guid>
      <description>Changing colors in Terminal I utilize Command Line Interfaces (CLI) frequently, Linux, Unix, Mac etc. Small adjustments to the CLI can make huge impacts on my workflow. Readability of the screen is very important, and I personally prefer a slightly higher contrast display. What I mean by that is on a bright background I prefer dark foreground colors, and on a dark background I prefer bright foreground colors. Unfortuantly the out of the box configuration does not always allow that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes how to patch external address into service</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-patch-service-external/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-patch-service-external/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This will be a quick short blog entry. Today I had an container running Oracle at Amazon EC2 on Kubernetes. I was trying to work thorugh some Pl/SQL code in sqlplus, and decided I wanted to instead use SQL Developer. After a little research this is what I came up with, and wanted to share it.
Bash Script kubectl patch svc oracle -p &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;spec&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;externalIPs&amp;#34;:[&amp;#34;1.2.3.4&amp;#34;]}}&amp;#39; Basically you pass the kubernetes service name, as well as your ip address of the host (in this example 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure SSH to keep from timing out</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-ssh-keepalive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-ssh-keepalive/</guid>
      <description>SSH Keep Alive Secure Shell is a means to connect terminals to servers. When it detects you are idle it disconnects you. This is for security. This however is very annoying and can cause issues if you are installing something and need to keep the terminal active. Some people try to leave &amp;rsquo;top&amp;rsquo; running or &amp;lsquo;screen&amp;rsquo; to keep the terminal busy. There is a simple configuration that can just as easily do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the colors in BASH</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-bash-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-bash-colors/</guid>
      <description>Changing colors in BASH So I find some color combations very hard to read. If you have a black background, the dark blue directory color is hard to read. If you have a white background the bright green executable color is hard to read. For whatever reason it was not thought very well through to have well contrasting colors for everything. I found this Ask Ubunutu on how to change the directory colors and decided to write a blog post to make sure I never lost the steps again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.4 with CRI-Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.4 with Docker and CRI-Docker. We are using an r5.2xlarge on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Ubuntu 22.4. You can get by with a much smaller instance depending on what you plan to run.
Installation Update Ubuntu Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
## Update Ubunutu sudo bash sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y sudo apt autoremove -y # if you see kenerl updates you should reboot # init 6 Hostname Your hostname should be in /etc/hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Windows share to Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-map-windows-to-unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-map-windows-to-unix/</guid>
      <description>Mounting Windows on Linux Setup on Ubuntu sudo apt-get install keyutils sudo apt-get install cifs-utils Setup on Redhat sudo yum install keyutils cifs-utils Syntax UNC=server.domain.com/share USERNAME=yourwindowslogin DOMAIN=NAMEOFDOMAIN PASSWORD=yourpassword sudo mkdir -p /mnt/${UNC} sudo mount -t cifs -o username=${USERNAME},domain=${DOMAIN},password=${PASSWORD} //${UNC} /mnt/${UNC} </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workspace with Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Amazon Workspace is a hosted Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI). Amazon hosts your workstations in the cloud. Users can connect to their provisioned workstations through a client software provided by Amazon for many different platforms, including mobile. The key difference comparing this to EC2 instances, is the client software. With EC2 typically you use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) or Secure Shell (SSH). With Amazon Workspace utilize PCoIP or WSP. Both protocals work far superior for end user experience for responsivness, espically on lower speed networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y # Kernel Updates wanted a reboot sudo init 6 Install ubuntu-desktop (Gnome, Xwindows, etc) sudo apt-get install ubuntu-desktop -y Install XRDP sudo apt install xrdp net-tools -y # insure xrpd on on ipv4 sudo sed -i &amp;#39;s/^port=3389/port=tcp:\/\/:3389/g&amp;#39; /etc/xrdp/xrdp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions to automatically build Docker and push to registry</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub provies &amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; which are automatic actions that are ran on gitHub for you. This can be used to compile your code, compile your docker image, or do any arbitrary set of commands. This typically is done in software development to automatically push software between development and test. This is typically done to insure all the necessary code, configurations, etc necessary are checked into the source repository. Additionally this insures all the neccessary steps are done uniformly no matter which developer checks in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes init container to verify dependent service(s) are online.</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-init-container-check-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-init-container-check-service/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With HELM Scripts containers all try to start at the same time. It depends on how the containers scripts were designed on if there is any sort of delay or dependency cchecking built into them. I wrote a very simple busybox script that can be used to prevent a container from starting until the kubernetes services is needs are available.
In this example there are 3 checks going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions copy one git repository to another git repository</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub provies &amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; which are automatic actions that are ran on gitHub for you. This can be used to compile your code, compile your docker image, or do any arbitrary set of commands. This typically is done in software development to automatically push software between development and test. This is typically done to insure all the necessary code, configurations, etc necessary are checked into the source repository. Additionally this insures all the neccessary steps are done uniformly no matter which developer checks in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo install on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction HUGO is a static website rendering engine. Essentially you write a collection of Mark Down to files with headers, and HUGO can very rapidily theme an entire website. This website for instance is on the HUGO platform. Other very large sites like most likely the Kubernetes Documentation is also on HUGO. You end up with a &amp;ldquo;wordpress&amp;rdquo; like feel for the end user, however its actually static HTML that can be served up on git pages or any http server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Web Services (AWS) Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I will be installing and doing basic configuration of Amazon Web Services (AWS)&amp;rsquo;s Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11. AWS CLI is a shell based means to work with AWS. The CLI provides the ability to list out resources at Amazon like which EC2 instances are running, poke around S3 buckets, inspect pretty much anything at Amazon. It also provides advanced features like copying information to and from S3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancher Desktop for Kubernetes and Docker on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rancher Desktop is a Kubernetes and Docker platform that is a replacement for Docker Desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ll be installing and configuring it using the installation guide provided in Rancher&amp;rsquo;s Documentation Rancher is a replacement for Docker Desktop. Rancher provies you helm, kubernetes, docker, the CRI runtimes of dockerd or containerd kubernetes. It integrates in nicely with WSL if you wish to use Linux instead of Windows. Additionally it lets you choose which version of Kubernetes you want to run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Install &amp;ldquo;Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux&amp;rdquo; (EPEL).
sudo dnf install -y https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-9.noarch.rpm sudo dnf repolist sudo dnf makecache Install &amp;ldquo;Workstation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Server with GUI&amp;rdquo; (not both)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python HTTP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</guid>
      <description>python http server If you need a quick and easy webserver to copy files between servers, or from your server to your workstation all you need is Python, which is part of YUM and is on almost every redhat based linux server. Simple goto the directory you want to share, and a single command in the shell will start up a webserver that you can use to get your files copied over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on RHEL 9 with CRI-O, and Podman. We are using an r5.large on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Setup DNS or atleast Hostname entries in your /etc/hosts file
echo `/sbin/ifconfig eth0 | grep &amp;#39;inet &amp;#39; | awk {&amp;#39;print $2&amp;#39;}` ${HOSTNAME} | sudo tee -a /etc/hosts Set selinux to permissive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
