<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nathan Obert</title>
    <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nathan Obert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 08:28:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Redhat Enterprise Linux 8</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel8/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on RHEL 8 with CRI-O, and Podman. We are using an r5.large on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y sudo dnf install net-tools -y Setup DNS or atleast Hostname entries in your /etc/hosts file
sudo hostnamectl set-hostname k8.obert.dev sudo init 6 echo `/sbin/ifconfig eth0 | grep &amp;#39;inet &amp;#39; | awk {&amp;#39;print $2&amp;#39;}` ${HOSTNAME} | sudo tee -a /etc/hosts Set selinux to permissive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get recursive folder path from Alfresco</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-alfresco-recursive-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-alfresco-recursive-sql/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Alfresco is a Content Management System, recently purchased by Hyland. I needed to write a query for Oracle and Microsoft SQL that would loop through its database and build a folder structure recursivily from its tables. These snippets of SQL are what I came up with.
Microsoft SQL Server This Article here is probably the best article I&amp;rsquo;ve found that explains MS SQL Recursion with a working example. https://www.andrewvillazon.com/recursive-cte-sql-server/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to update Alfresco password(s) from database</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-alfresco-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-alfresco-password/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Alfresco is a Content Management System, recently purchased by Hyland. I needed the steps to reset the admin password through the database. I decided to document the steps here.
Inspect passwords The passwords are stored in essentially NTLM format (utf16le encoded in md4 hash). You can&amp;rsquo;t really turn a hash back into a password, however you could obviously turn a string into a hash. This could possibly be brute forced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes how create folders for Physical Volumes (PVs) automatically</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-k8-init-create-pv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-k8-init-create-pv/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This will be a quick short blog entry. Today I needed to have a container that could self-initialize it&amp;rsquo;s own Physical Volumes. This is quite easy to do with an init container. I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a simple example to show how this works with busybox.
Deployment YAML initContainers: - name: init-pv image: {{ .Values.initpv.image }} volumeMounts: - name: init mountPath: {{ .Values.persistentVolume.path }} {{- with .Values.initpv.command }} command: {{- toYaml .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes how inject commands before entrypoint</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-k8-update-entrypoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-k8-update-entrypoint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This will be a quick short blog entry. Today I had an image running on Kubernetes from a vender invoked through HELM, and I needed to run some arbtirary commands however I did not want to extend the image and have to deal with maintaining yet another image. Below is the solution I came up with.
YAML to inject commands before entry point. image: repository: docker.io/user/image pullPolicy: IfNotPresent tag: &amp;#34;latest&amp;#34; command: - bash - &amp;#34;-c&amp;#34; - | sed -i &amp;#39;s/^param=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the colors in Terminal ZSH on Mac OS</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/mac-cli-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/mac-cli-colors/</guid>
      <description>Changing colors in Terminal I utilize Command Line Interfaces (CLI) frequently, Linux, Unix, Mac etc. Small adjustments to the CLI can make huge impacts on my workflow. Readability of the screen is very important, and I personally prefer a slightly higher contrast display. What I mean by that is on a bright background I prefer dark foreground colors, and on a dark background I prefer bright foreground colors. Unfortuantly the out of the box configuration does not always allow that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes how to patch external address into service</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-patch-service-external/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-patch-service-external/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This will be a quick short blog entry. Today I had an container running Oracle at Amazon EC2 on Kubernetes. I was trying to work thorugh some Pl/SQL code in sqlplus, and decided I wanted to instead use SQL Developer. After a little research this is what I came up with, and wanted to share it.
Bash Script kubectl patch svc oracle -p &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;spec&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;externalIPs&amp;#34;:[&amp;#34;1.2.3.4&amp;#34;]}}&amp;#39; Basically you pass the kubernetes service name, as well as your ip address of the host (in this example 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure SSH to keep from timing out</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-ssh-keepalive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-ssh-keepalive/</guid>
      <description>SSH Keep Alive Secure Shell is a means to connect terminals to servers. When it detects you are idle it disconnects you. This is for security. This however is very annoying and can cause issues if you are installing something and need to keep the terminal active. Some people try to leave &amp;rsquo;top&amp;rsquo; running or &amp;lsquo;screen&amp;rsquo; to keep the terminal busy. There is a simple configuration that can just as easily do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the colors in BASH</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-bash-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-bash-colors/</guid>
      <description>Changing colors in BASH So I find some color combations very hard to read. If you have a black background, the dark blue directory color is hard to read. If you have a white background the bright green executable color is hard to read. For whatever reason it was not thought very well through to have well contrasting colors for everything. I found this Ask Ubunutu on how to change the directory colors and decided to write a blog post to make sure I never lost the steps again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.4 with CRI-Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on Ubuntu 22.4 with Docker and CRI-Docker. We are using an r5.2xlarge on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Ubuntu 22.4. You can get by with a much smaller instance depending on what you plan to run.
Installation Update Ubuntu Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
## Update Ubunutu sudo bash sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y sudo apt autoremove -y # if you see kenerl updates you should reboot # init 6 Hostname Your hostname should be in /etc/hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Windows share to Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-map-windows-to-unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-map-windows-to-unix/</guid>
      <description>Mounting Windows on Linux Setup on Ubuntu sudo apt-get install keyutils sudo apt-get install cifs-utils Setup on Redhat sudo yum install keyutils cifs-utils Syntax UNC=server.domain.com/share USERNAME=yourwindowslogin DOMAIN=NAMEOFDOMAIN PASSWORD=yourpassword sudo mkdir -p /mnt/${UNC} sudo mount -t cifs -o username=${USERNAME},domain=${DOMAIN},password=${PASSWORD} //${UNC} /mnt/${UNC} </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workspace with Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-workspace-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Amazon Workspace is a hosted Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI). Amazon hosts your workstations in the cloud. Users can connect to their provisioned workstations through a client software provided by Amazon for many different platforms, including mobile. The key difference comparing this to EC2 instances, is the client software. With EC2 typically you use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) or Secure Shell (SSH). With Amazon Workspace utilize PCoIP or WSP. Both protocals work far superior for end user experience for responsivness, espically on lower speed networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates sudo apt update -y sudo apt upgrade -y # Kernel Updates wanted a reboot sudo init 6 Install ubuntu-desktop (Gnome, Xwindows, etc) sudo apt-get install ubuntu-desktop -y Install XRDP sudo apt install xrdp net-tools -y # insure xrpd on on ipv4 sudo sed -i &amp;#39;s/^port=3389/port=tcp:\/\/:3389/g&amp;#39; /etc/xrdp/xrdp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions to automatically build Docker and push to registry</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub provies &amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; which are automatic actions that are ran on gitHub for you. This can be used to compile your code, compile your docker image, or do any arbitrary set of commands. This typically is done in software development to automatically push software between development and test. This is typically done to insure all the necessary code, configurations, etc necessary are checked into the source repository. Additionally this insures all the neccessary steps are done uniformly no matter which developer checks in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes init container to verify dependent service(s) are online.</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-init-container-check-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-init-container-check-service/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With HELM Scripts containers all try to start at the same time. It depends on how the containers scripts were designed on if there is any sort of delay or dependency cchecking built into them. I wrote a very simple busybox script that can be used to prevent a container from starting until the kubernetes services is needs are available.
In this example there are 3 checks going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions copy one git repository to another git repository</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-github-actions-copy-repo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub provies &amp;ldquo;Actions&amp;rdquo; which are automatic actions that are ran on gitHub for you. This can be used to compile your code, compile your docker image, or do any arbitrary set of commands. This typically is done in software development to automatically push software between development and test. This is typically done to insure all the necessary code, configurations, etc necessary are checked into the source repository. Additionally this insures all the neccessary steps are done uniformly no matter which developer checks in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo install on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 05:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-hugo-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction HUGO is a static website rendering engine. Essentially you write a collection of Mark Down to files with headers, and HUGO can very rapidily theme an entire website. This website for instance is on the HUGO platform. Other very large sites like most likely the Kubernetes Documentation is also on HUGO. You end up with a &amp;ldquo;wordpress&amp;rdquo; like feel for the end user, however its actually static HTML that can be served up on git pages or any http server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Web Services (AWS) Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I will be installing and doing basic configuration of Amazon Web Services (AWS)&amp;rsquo;s Command Line Interface (CLI) on Windows 11. AWS CLI is a shell based means to work with AWS. The CLI provides the ability to list out resources at Amazon like which EC2 instances are running, poke around S3 buckets, inspect pretty much anything at Amazon. It also provides advanced features like copying information to and from S3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS CLI Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 04:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This cheat sheet from Applo Clark&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet. Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Official CLI Documentation. Amazon Web Services (AWS)&amp;rsquo;s Command Line Interface (CLI) is a shell based means to work with AWS. The CLI provides the ability to list out resources at Amazon like which EC2 instances are running, poke around S3 buckets, inspect pretty much anything at Amazon. It also provides advanced features like copying information to and from S3. Below is a cheat sheet I will be updating over time with frequently used commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HELM Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-helm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction &amp;ldquo;Helm is the best way to find, share, and use software built for Kubernetes.&amp;rdquo; Kubernetes is a great container orchistration tool, however managing all the yaml files associated with it become a huge undertaking. Helm is a tool that allows you to create templates for Kubernetes yaml files. Then you only have to manage a set a value pairs that are passed to your templates. This allows you to easily share packages of templates, and other people can easily bring your containers online only having to modify the values to match their needs to customize or configure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancher Desktop for Kubernetes and Docker on Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-rancher-desktop-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rancher Desktop is a Kubernetes and Docker platform that is a replacement for Docker Desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ll be installing and configuring it using the installation guide provided in Rancher&amp;rsquo;s Documentation Rancher is a replacement for Docker Desktop. Rancher provies you helm, kubernetes, docker, the CRI runtimes of dockerd or containerd kubernetes. It integrates in nicely with WSL if you wish to use Linux instead of Windows. Additionally it lets you choose which version of Kubernetes you want to run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-git/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This cheat sheet from Alex arak14&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet. Git is a version constrol system often used by developers, and devops to store insource code and configurations. It has even been adapted to store websites that are rended to the internet (like this one!) using Hugo. Git repositories are distributed in that each developers has a local copy of the repository and a series of pushs, pulls, merges, forks occur for the repositories to synchronize with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XRP to remote Gnome on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-xrdp-gnome-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be turning a Command Line Interface (CLI) Redhat 9 server hosted at Amazon on EC2 into a full Xwindows based workstation that you can use Remote Desktop Protocal (RDP) to using xRDP.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Install &amp;ldquo;Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux&amp;rdquo; (EPEL).
sudo dnf install -y https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-9.noarch.rpm sudo dnf repolist sudo dnf makecache Install &amp;ldquo;Workstation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Server with GUI&amp;rdquo; (not both)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python HTTP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 12:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-python-http-server/</guid>
      <description>python http server If you need a quick and easy webserver to copy files between servers, or from your server to your workstation all you need is Python, which is part of YUM and is on almost every redhat based linux server. Simple goto the directory you want to share, and a single command in the shell will start up a webserver that you can use to get your files copied over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Sematext&amp;rsquo;s Docker Cheatsheet
Docker Cheatsheet Tutorial series Get started with Docker: https://docs.docker.com/engine/getstarted/
Installation Linux Install script provided by Docker:
curl -sSL https://get.docker.com/ | sh Or see Installation instructions for your Linux distribution.
Mac OS X Download and install Docker For Mac
Create Docker VM with Docker Machine You can use Docker Machine to:
Install and run Docker on Mac or Windows Provision and manage multiple remote Docker hosts Provision Swarm clusters A simple example to create a local Docker VM with VirtualBox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Developer Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-elastic-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-elastic-dev/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Sematext&amp;rsquo;s Elastic Developer Cheatsheet
Data Manipulation Put/Get/Delete index curl -XPUT localhost:9200/index-name -d &#39;{&amp;quot;settings&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;number_of_shards&amp;quot;: 1}}&#39; curl -XGET localhost:9200/index-name?pretty curl -XDELETE localhost:9200/index-name Put/Get/Delete template curl -XPUT localhost:9200/_template/template-name -d &#39;{ &amp;quot;template&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs*&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;mappings&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;foo-type&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;properties&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;foo-field&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;text&amp;quot; } } } }, &amp;quot;settings&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;number_of_shards&amp;quot;: 1 } }&#39; curl -XGET localhost:9200/_template/template-name?pretty curl -XDELETE localhost:9200/_template/template-name Bulk API echo &#39;{&amp;quot;index&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;_index&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs01&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;_type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs&amp;quot;}} {&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;this is an error&amp;quot;} {&amp;quot;index&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;_index&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs02&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;_type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs&amp;quot;}} {&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;this is a warning&amp;quot;} {&amp;quot;delete&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;_index&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs03&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;_type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;logs&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;abc123&amp;quot;}} &#39; &amp;gt; /tmp/bulk curl localhost:9200/_bulk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Devops Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-elastic-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-elastic-devops/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Sematext&amp;rsquo;s Elastic Devops Cheatsheet
DevOps cheatsheet Allocation Allocation awareness Avoids putting two copies of the same shard on nodes with the same attribute (e.g. rack, availability zone). For example:
node.attr.availability_zone: us-east1 # in elasticsearch.yml Awareness is enabled at the cluster level:
curl -XPUT localhost:9200/_cluster/settings?pretty -d &#39;{ &amp;quot;persistent&amp;quot; : { &amp;quot;cluster.routing.allocation.awareness.attributes&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;availability_zone&amp;quot; } }&#39; Allocation filtering Shards of an index can prefer/avoid nodes with certain attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLR Metrics Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-solr-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-solr-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Sematext&amp;rsquo;s SOLR Metric&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet
Solr Metrics API Retrieving all Metrics
Get all metrics:
localhost:8983/solr/admin/metrics
Retrieving Metrics for Specific Group
Metrics for a group (groups: solr.jvm, solr.node, solr.jetty, solr.core.&amp;lt;collection_name&amp;gt;):
localhost:8983/solr/admin/metrics?group=solr.jvm
Retrieving Metrics in JSON
Default is XML. For JSON:
localhost:8983/solr/admin/metrics?wt=json
localhost:8983/solr/admin/metrics?wt=json&amp;amp;indent=true
Jetty Metrics Number of Requests with Given Response Status
Check the number of requests with the given HTTP status, useful when checking for number of errors and successful requests:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Kubernetes Website&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet.
This page contains a list of commonly used kubectl commands and flags.
Kubectl autocomplete BASH source &amp;lt;(kubectl completion bash) # set up autocomplete in bash into the current shell, bash-completion package should be installed first. echo &amp;#34;source &amp;lt;(kubectl completion bash)&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc # add autocomplete permanently to your bash shell. You can also use a shorthand alias for kubectl that also works with completion:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-openssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-openssl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This cheat sheet from Dave Wongillies&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet. OpenSSL is a very strong tool when working with certificates. OpenSSL can be used to for a wide variaty of taks involving SSL/TLS. For instance you can use it to convert certificates from format to another, use it as a debugging tool, use it to generate certificates, use it to download certificates from hosts, and even use it as a connectivity tool if telnet is not available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 05:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/cheatsheet-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a quick cheat sheet from Adam Pritchard&amp;rsquo;s Cheatsheet that is useful when writing markup to make sure the syntax is correct. Markdown is a syntax used to format text. It essentially is a short form version of Hypertext Mark Up Language (HTML). You can achieve similar formatting with far less effort and by writing in Markdown instead of HTML. There is a Live Demo of Markdown available. This is especially useful if you would like to see what the rendered interactively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Nathan Obert</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 20:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Professional I started writing code in 1980 when I was 5 years old. Atari Line Basic! I&amp;rsquo;ve have been doing Development and IT work since then. Most likely you have used, or your information is in one of the many systems i&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. I&amp;rsquo;m happily employeed at Armedia. My Resume is on Linked In if you would like to look it over. I graduated from George Mason University. I have a Master&amp;rsquo;s, Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s, and Associate&amp;rsquo;s in Computer Science, as well as a second Associate&amp;rsquo;s in Mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Redhat Enterprise Linux 9</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 08:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/blog-kubernetes-on-rhel9/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will install a Kubernetes on RHEL 9 with CRI-O, and Podman. We are using an r5.large on Amazon EC2 using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s provided Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
Installation Install the updates on your fresh server from Amazon.
sudo dnf update -y Setup DNS or atleast Hostname entries in your /etc/hosts file
echo `/sbin/ifconfig eth0 | grep &amp;#39;inet &amp;#39; | awk {&amp;#39;print $2&amp;#39;}` ${HOSTNAME} | sudo tee -a /etc/hosts Set selinux to permissive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Rent Camera Gear at LensRental.com</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/lensrental/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/lensrental/</guid>
      <description>Introduction How to Rent Camera Gear at LensRental.com
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowepro Truckee BP 250 Camera Bag Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/lowspro-truckee-bp250/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/lowspro-truckee-bp250/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Review of the Lowepro Truckee BP 250 Camera Bag
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aputure MC RGBWW Led Light Unboxing</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/apature_mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/apature_mc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Today I unbox the Aputure MC RGBWW Led Light. I review the capability and use of the aputure light.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmallRig 1/4” to Hotshoe Adapter</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/smallrig_hotshoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/smallrig_hotshoe/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We provide a quick unboxing and review of the SmallRig 1/4” to Hotshoe Adapter.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GorillaPod RIG 5K Unboxing and Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/gorillapod_5k/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/gorillapod_5k/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Today we review and Unbox a GorillaPod RIG 5K. The GorillaPod is the standard for VLOGGERS, and the RIG provides additional features.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haida Installation on Sony FE 1.7 / 14 GM</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/haida_nd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/haida_nd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What are ND Filters &amp;amp; Haida Installation on Sony FE 1.7 / 14 GM. Today we first explain what ND filters are, how they can be used. We tackle how to install ND Filters, and finally we will install a rear Haida ND filter on the Sony FE 1.7 / 14 GM Lens.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to stream video using Sony A7IV</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/a7iv_livestream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/a7iv_livestream/</guid>
      <description>Introduction How to stream video using Sony A7IV. I provide instructions on how to setup Live Streaming with the Sony A7IV on Mac and Windows.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony FE 1.8 / 14 GM Lens Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/sony-14gm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathanobert.com/posts/sony-14gm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Review of Photography with the Sony FE 1.8 / 14 GM Lens, using Sony A7IV.
Video </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
